<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Techniques on Sidecar</title>
    <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Techniques on Sidecar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 13:07:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Straining</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/straining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 13:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/straining/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;TODO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;double-straining&#34;&gt;Double Straining&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>twist</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:07:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/twist/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:07:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are three techniques for making a cocktail: building, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/shaking&#34;&gt;shaking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/stirring&#34;&gt;stirring&lt;/a&gt;. It’s important to know when to use which method.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building&lt;/em&gt; a cocktail is the easiest method. Start by adding ice to the serving glass (if needed), then measure the ingredients one-by-one and pour them over the ice. Sometimes a quick stir is needed to incorate the ingredients together. Finally, top with any garnish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highball drinks are built, such as Jack &amp;amp; Coke, Seven &amp;amp; Seven, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/gin-and-tonic/&#34;&gt;Gin &amp;amp; Tonic&lt;/a&gt;. A handful of other cocktails are typically built as well, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/old-fashioned/&#34;&gt;Old Fashioned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/built/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged built&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stirring</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/stirring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:07:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/stirring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are three techniques for making a cocktail: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/building/&#34;&gt;building&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/shaking/&#34;&gt;shaking&lt;/a&gt;, and stirring. It’s important to know when to use which method.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stirring a drink sounds easy. But of the three techniques, stirring a drink takes the most practice to get right. Here’s how it’s done (or watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KCusyYyoltA&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measure the ingredients and pour them into the base of a cocktail shaker or into a mixing glass. Then add plenty of ice. There needs to be enough ice that the weight of ice on top pushes the rest of the ice to the bottom of the shaker, not just floating on top. This is important to increase the amount of ice that’s in contact with the drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insert a bar spoon along the edge of the shaker so that the back edge of the spoon is touching the metal (or glass). Hold the bar spoon loosely between your second and third fingers, allowing to to spin freely as you stir. By curling then extending your fingers, you should be able to pull the bar spoon toward you with your bottom of your index and middle finger, then push it away from you with the tops of your ring and pinky fingers. The spoon should rotate around the edges of the mixing glass, with the back of the spoon in constant contact with the glass. This should spin the ice smoothly, without rattling it around. Rattling the ice can break off small chips of ice that over-dilute the drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;practice-makes-perfect&#34;&gt;Practice Makes Perfect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some practice to get familiar with this motion. When I first started, I had a cheap, flimsy bar spoon, and I had a hard time getting a feel for it. It was easier after I upgraded to one that is evenly weighted so I was pushing and pulling it near its center of gravity. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IRY8CJ2/&#34;&gt;This is the bar spoon&lt;/a&gt; I use.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should stir the drink for 20&amp;ndash;30 seconds. This is longer than you think, so use a timer or count slowly in your head until you get a feel for it. Stirring will melt the ice into the drink, chilling it and diluting it appropriately. The longer you stir, the more dilution you will get, but unless you stir for a very long time, this will still introduce less water than &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/shaking/&#34;&gt;shaking&lt;/a&gt;. It’s important to melt enough water into the drink or it won’t be properly balanced&amp;mdash;just try a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/negroni/&#34;&gt;Negroni&lt;/a&gt; that hasn’t been stirred enough; it’s not very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, strain the drink into the serving glass and add the garnish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/stirred/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged stirred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaking</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/shaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:07:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/shaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are three techniques for making a cocktail: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/building/&#34;&gt;building&lt;/a&gt;, shaking, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/stirring/&#34;&gt;stirring&lt;/a&gt;. It’s important to know when to use which method.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;Shake&lt;/em&gt; a cocktail, measure the ingredients and add them to a cocktail shaker, along with plenty of ice. If the drink is to be served on the rocks, add fresh ice to the glass, too. Put the top on the shaker, then holding it with both hands, shake it above your shoulder. Shake for about ten seconds, or until the shaker frosts up thoroughly. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/techniques/straining/&#34;&gt;strain the drink&lt;/a&gt; into the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaken drinks are typically those that contain anything other than pure alcohol. If a recipe calls for any juice (such as lemon or lime), cream, or egg white, it should be shaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some shaken drinks, such as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/french-75/&#34;&gt;French 75&lt;/a&gt;, call for sparkling wine. When this is the case, add all the liquids &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; the sparkling wine to the shaker. Shake as normal and strain into the glass. Then top with the sparkling wine and add any garnish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-shaking&#34;&gt;The Purpose of Shaking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaking a cocktail does two things: it melts ice into the drink and it adds texture. Melting ice simultaneously chills the drink and adds water to it. Shaking is the fastest way to do that. Shaking a cocktail will typically add around 1 oz of water, give or take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The texture is also important. Shaking froths up the drink with small air bubbles. This makes it feel slightly thicker on the tongue. After shaking the drink, these bubbles will start to break up, so serve the drink while it’s fresh. Ingredients that contain protein (such as egg white or honey) will strengthen these bubbles, making the drink frothier and longer-lasting in the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dry-shaking&#34;&gt;Dry Shaking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dry shaking is a method to add extra froth to the top of the drink. Most drinks containing egg benefit from dry shaking. (It also helps break up the egg and incorporate it into the drink better.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To dry shake, first add the ingredients to the shaker &lt;em&gt;without any ice&lt;/em&gt;. Hold the shaker closed tightly and shake vigorously for at least 10 seconds, but preferably as long as 20 or 30 seconds. The longer you shake, the more froth will build up. Then, open up the shaker and add the ice. Close it up and give it another good shake for around ten seconds. Then strain into the serving glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful&lt;/strong&gt; when dry shaking. Normal shaking with ice chills the drink, making it contract, which creates a suction and holds your shaker closed. Without the ice, there is no suction, so the shaker is much more prone to come open while shaking. I have made a lot of messes dry shaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reverse-dry-shaking&#34;&gt;Reverse Dry Shaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reverse dry shaking is a method to increase the amount of froth on top of the drink even more. First shake &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; ice, then strain out the ice and shake the drink again &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, this will produce more froth after ice has been diluted in the drink, so the ice doesn&amp;rsquo;t start to break some of the froth up. In my experience, I have a hard time telling whether this works better than a normal dry shake. It’s a bit of a hassle to strain out the ice between shakes, but it does seem to maintain suction in the shaker during the no-ice shake, meaning fewer spills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/shaken/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged shaken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>