<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Built on Sidecar</title>
    <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/built/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Built on Sidecar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:59:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/built/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gin and Tonic</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/gin-and-tonic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:59:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/gin-and-tonic/</guid>
      <description>A deceptively simple drink, these particular instructions are meant to minimize the amount of carbonation lost from the tonic water. Recipe by Dave Arnold.
Traditionally made with a London dry gin, but I think it’s fantastic with genever-style gin.
 1¾ oz gin3¼ oz tonic water¼ lime, wedge Pre-chill a rocks glass and gin in the freezer.
Add the gin to the rocks glass. Gently pour in the tonic water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GBC</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/gbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:44:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/gbc/</guid>
      <description> A refreshing, summery drink. 1 oz gin½ oz lime juice¼ oz simple syrup3 basil leaves, sliced into strips4 cucumber slices1½ tonic water Middle basil leaves, three cucumber slices, and simple syrup in the base of a rocks glass. Add the gin and lime, and crushed ice.
Top with tonic water. Garnish with slice of cucumber.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definitive Irish Coffee</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/irish-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 11:54:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/irish-coffee/</guid>
      <description>This approach uses burnt sugar syrup instead of granulated sugar, so I take pains to warm it and the whiskey before mixing with the coffee to avoid a lukewarm drink.
Technically, any Irish whiskey will work, but you really ought to use Tullamore Dew.
 1 oz Irish whiskey¾ oz burnt sugar syrup3½ oz extra strong fresh-brewed coffee1 oz cream, whipped until thick and frothy but still pourable Brew your coffee with the normal amount of grounds but half the normal amount of water so it is extra strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Fashioned</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/old-fashioned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 11:30:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/old-fashioned/</guid>
      <description>Some people will argue an Old Fashioned must be made with a sugar cube. Those people haven’t tried it with burnt sugar syrup. 2 oz rye whiskey¾ oz burnt sugar syrup2 dashes Angostura bitters2 dashes orange bittersorange twist Add ice to a rocks glass. Add both bitters, then the whiskey and burnt sugar syrup. The syrup will sink to the bottom, so give it a quick stir to mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Kiss</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/french-kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 12:21:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/french-kiss/</guid>
      <description> As always, use only high quality vermouth that is fresh (less than three months old). 2 oz sweet vermouth2 oz dry vermouth Build in a rocks glass. Garnish with a lemon twist.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>