<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stirred on Sidecar</title>
    <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/stirred/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stirred on Sidecar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 12:27:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/stirred/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>El Presidente</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/el-presidente/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 12:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/el-presidente/</guid>
      <description> 1½ oz white rum¾ oz curaçao or orange liqueur¾ oz dry vermouthdash of grenadineorange twist Stir all liquids with ice. Strain into a coupe glass. Garnish with orange twist.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manhattan</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/manhattan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 11:31:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/manhattan/</guid>
      <description> 2 oz rye whiskey1 oz sweet vermouth2 dashes Angostura bitters Combine in a shaker with ice. Stir, then strain into a coupe glass.
Garnish with a Maraschino cherry.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martini</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/martini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 11:30:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/martini/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has an opinion about martinis. I’ll spare you mine, and just give you my recipe. Trust me.
I often use a blanc vermouth instead of the traditional dry, but it’s delicious with either. Any type of gin works in a martini, but I prefer a sweeter style.
 2¼ oz genever gin¾ oz dry vermouth Add to cocktail shaker with plenty of ice. Stir well, then strain into a martini glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negroni</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/negroni/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 21:27:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/negroni/</guid>
      <description>The Negroni is my favorite drink. It’s quite sweet, but also bitter and complex. I make mine with Tanquery gin and Cocchi di Torino vermouth. It can also be served on the rocks, but I prefer it neat.
This drink is a great test of your stirring skills. It really falls flat if you don’t stir it properly.
 1 oz Campari1 oz London dry gin1 oz sweet vermouthorange twist Add all liquids to a mixing glass along with plenty of ice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>