<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ingredients on Sidecar</title>
    <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ingredients on Sidecar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:09:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnt Sugar Syrup</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/burnt-sugar-syrup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/burnt-sugar-syrup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love burnt sugar syrup. It’s complex flavor does really well in many cocktails. It also works well in coffee and lattes. It’s less sweet than regular simple syrup, so I use a little more of this when swapping them out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;aside&#34;&gt;I use equal parts of water and sugar, by weight. I realize now that this is unconventional, as most recipes call for less water. I need to try that and adjust my recipes accordingly.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the sugar to a saucepan and heat over medium-high heat. Do not stir it. After several minutes, the sugar will begin to melt and bubble. If you still have dry sugar on top, stir it in so it melts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow the sugar to heat for a few more minutes until it is a light brown color. The longer you heat it, the darker it will get&amp;mdash;and the less sweet the resulting syrup will be. Don’t go too dark, however, or it will really burn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove from heat and slowly add the water. &lt;strong&gt;Be careful&lt;/strong&gt; as the mixture will boil angrily and will release steam that can burn you. (Melted sugar is well above the boiling temperature of water!) Once it calms back down, stir together. The sugar will often seize up, which is okay. Return the pan to medium low heat and stir until the seized sugar has dissolved back into a liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow this to cool and store it in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/burnt-sugar-syrup&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged burnt-sugar-syrup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-caramel-sauce&#34;&gt;Bonus: Caramel Sauce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can make burnt sugar syrup, you’re not far off from making amazing homemade caramel sauce to go on ice cream or other desserts. The only fundamental difference is caramel sauce is made with cream instead of water. And often a little salt and butter is added to enhance the flavor. Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mybakingaddiction.com/fundamentals-how-to-make-homemade-caramel-sauce/&#34;&gt;caramel sauce recipe&lt;/a&gt; I use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Syrup</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/simple-syrup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/simple-syrup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An essential in every bar, simple syrup is a way to add sweetness to drinks. Regular sugar won’t do because it doesn’t dissolve readily into cold ingredients.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make simple syrup, add equal amounts (&lt;em&gt;by weight&lt;/em&gt;) of sugar and water in a saucepan. Heat, stirring occasionally, until the sugar dissolves; it will look clear. Don’t boil it, or you will lose water to evaporation. Allow it to cool, then bottle it and store it in your refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also make simple syrup in a blender. Just add the water and sugar and blend until dissolved. The benefit of this is you don’t have to wait for it to cool, so you can us it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;variations&#34;&gt;Variations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substitute other types of sugar for different syrups. Use demerara sugar to make a demerara syrup or brown sugar for a brown sugar syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flavor-infusion&#34;&gt;Flavor Infusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can infusing flavors into your syrup to make your cocktails really stand out. Make your syrup on the stove as normal. Then, immediately after turning off the heat, add the ingredient(s) you would like to infuse into the syrup and allow it to steep in the hot syrup as it cools. When it’s cool, strain out the solids and store in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can infuse just about anything you can think of. Here are some ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;berries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dried chilies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blackberry and lavender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black peppercorns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cardamom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinnamon and pear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right flavored syrup can take an otherwise simple cocktail to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/burnt-sugar-syrup/&#34;&gt;burnt-sugar-syrup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;honey-syrup&#34;&gt;Honey Syrup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honey is just a little too thick to incorporate easily into cocktails. You can make a syrup by adding a little water and heating to dissolve the honey in. For every 100 grams of honey, add 64 grams of water (about a 3:2 ratio). This will result in a syrup with about the same sweetness as simple syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add infusions to honey syrup the same ways as you can with simple syrup. I infuse cardamom to make a cardomom honey syrup for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/indian-winter/&#34;&gt;Indian Winter&lt;/a&gt; cocktail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gin</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/gin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:09:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/gin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gin is a liquor flavored with juniper berries. When you think of gin, you most likely picture a London Dry gin, such as Tanqueray. Not all gins are created equal, however. In many cocktails, using the right type of gin is essential.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bonappetit.com/story/different-types-of-gin&#34;&gt;four general categories of gin&lt;/a&gt;. Some people will subdivide this further&amp;mdash;in my recipes, I try to keep my definitions broader to leave more room for interpretation and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get a good feel for any of these types of gin, use it in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/martini/&#34;&gt;martini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;london-dry-gin&#34;&gt;London Dry Gin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most commonly-known type of gin. In &lt;em&gt;London Dry&lt;/em&gt; gin, the juniper flavor is dominant. It’ typically the least sweet of the gins. Common brands include Tanqueray, Beefeater, and Bombay Sapphire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/london-dry-gin/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged london-dry-gin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;genever-gin&#34;&gt;Genever Gin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the opposite end of the spectrum is &lt;em&gt;Genever&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;Jenever&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Dutch Style&lt;/em&gt;) Gin. This is the oldest style of gin. It still uses juniper, but it is balanced with a wide array of other botanical flavors. Genever gins may include flavors of vanilla, coriander, flowers, nutmeg, anise, or orange. It often tastes more malty than other gins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the European Union, only gins made in the Netherlands, Belgium, France, or Germany may be labelled as genever. The names &lt;em&gt;New American&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;International&lt;/em&gt; style may be applied to similar gins produced elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hendrick’s and Bols Genever are two well-known Genever-style gin. My personal favorite gin, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aviationgin.com/&#34;&gt;Aviation&lt;/a&gt; also falls in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/genever-gin/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged genever-gin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-tom-gin&#34;&gt;Old Tom Gin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old Tom&lt;/em&gt; gin is sweeter than a London Dry but has a more dominant juniper flavor than many Genever gins. It tends to fall in the middle of the road between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for Hayman’s or Ransom brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/old-tom-gin/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged old-tom-gin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plymouth-gin&#34;&gt;Plymouth Gin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plymouth&lt;/em&gt; gin is dryer than London Dry gin, but has a stronger citrus flavor and a spicier finish. There is only one brand of Plymouth gin and it’s Plymouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/tags/plymouth-gin/&#34;&gt;Drinks tagged plymouth-gin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vermouth</title>
      <link>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/vermouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:09:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/ingredients/vermouth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vermouth is type of fortified wine with added hints of various herbs and spices. It’s a common ingredient in many cocktails, the most well-known being the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/martini&#34;&gt;martini&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-vermouth&#34;&gt;Types of Vermouth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two most common types of vermouth are &lt;em&gt;dry&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sweet&lt;/em&gt;. Dry vermouths are light in color, often with a hint of yellow. The quintessential dry vermouth drink is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/martini&#34;&gt;martini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet vermouths, often labelled “Rosso”, are reddish in color and sweeter tasting than dry vermouths. The best-known sweet vermouth drink is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/manhattan&#34;&gt;manhattan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another less common type of vermouth are “blanc” or “bianco”. Blanc vermouth is clear in color, but sweeter in flavor than a dry vermouth. These are delicous and in some ways similar to Sherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;brands&#34;&gt;Brands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;aside&#34;&gt;
The most readily-available brand of vermouth (in the U.S.) is &lt;i&gt;Martini &amp; Rossi&lt;/i&gt;. Their dry vermouth is passable, but there are better options available. Their sweet vermouth is overly medicinal and a quick way to ruin a drink.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vermouth is often under-appreciated, largely because old bottles of Martini &amp;amp; Rossi are all you will find in most home liquor cabinets. I recommend the following brands (my favorites at the top). You may need to visit a larger liquor store to find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dolin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cocchi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carpano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lillet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noilly Prat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;storing-vermouth&#34;&gt;Storing Vermouth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vermouth is made from wine, so &lt;strong&gt;it goes bad&lt;/strong&gt;! Once you’ve opened a bottle, store it in your fridge. It will be good there for about three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure, taste a little. If it tastes bad, it’s bad. If you have an old dusty bottle on your shelf, throw it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have some fresh, high quality vermouth, try out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidecar.keithjgrant.com/drinks/french-kiss&#34;&gt;French Kiss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>